#### Vaibhav Sharma

Address: 318 Horn Lane, North Acton, W3 6TH

Mobile: 07424951533

Email: sharma.vaibhav612@gmail.com

### Personal Profile

A highly experienced and competent IT support Engineer with seven years' experience in a variety of office-based environments. A level head and rational approach to problem solving leads to reliability and fast solutions to IT technical issues. An excellent communicator with the ability to explain procedures in a practical and user-friendly way means that many IT problems can be solved via the telephone.

Comfortable working as part of a team or independently with a focus on delivering quality IT support on a continuous basis.

# Education and IT Training 10/06/2017 - 10/10/2017

Just IT Training Ltd, London

### **Network Professional Program**

- CompTIA A+ Essentials (Passed)
- CompTIA A+ IT Technician (Passed)
- MCTS Windows 10 (passed)
- MCTS Windows Server 2012 (Expected soon)
- Cisco CCNA (Expected soon)
- ITIL Fundamentals

### **ADDITIONAL COURSES**

- Information security (passed)
- Vb.net(passed)
- Networking with Linux (passed)
- Asp.Net(passed)
- Pc financial accounting Tally (passed)
- ITES-BPO (Passed)

04/2013-11/2014 University of Bedfordshire, Luton Post graduate Certificate Computer Networking (2:1)

Core Modules: Emerging Technologies, Network Systems, Network

Administration and Management, Wireless

Networking, Computer Security and Advanced Security

and Countermeasures

06/2011-10/2012 University of Bedfordshire, Luton
B Tech Computer System Engineering (2:2)

Core Modules: Research Methodologies and Emerging Technology,

Social and Project Management, Optimization and Engineering Applications and Individual Reports
"Positions of Polav Nodos in Mobile Networks"

Final Year Project: "Positions of Relay Nodes in Mobile Networks"

05/2008-01/2011 Institute of Engineering & Computer Science, India

Polytechnic (3 yrs.) Computer Engineering (2:1)

06/2007-06/2008 Air Force School, India

A Level: General English, Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics

(grade one)

06/2006-06/2007 Air Force School, India

General English, Physics, Chemistry, biology and Maths

06/2002-06/2006 Indian Army School, India

GCSE: English, Maths, Hindi and Social Science (grade one)

### **Employment History**

02/09/2019

Present Information and Communication Technology Engineer

(school business services)

- Vast experience in IT problems and solutions
- Working within a TCP/IP network environment, including DHCP, DNS and ethernet
- Provide secondary support for LAN administration
- Communicating with third party technical specialists
- Fully experienced in providing and maintaining IT security across large networks
- Deploying new hardware, server backups & evaluating new software & security risks
- Involved in the roll-out of software updates and patches.
- Broad knowledge and experience of IT operating systems including Microsoft Windows client operating systems, XP, Vista, Windows 10/ Windows & Microsoft Office, and Linux.
- Experienced google operating system and licences
- Handle office 365 and google chrome as admin

# IT Support Systems and Data Management (Baltic Exchange & SGX)

- Research, plan, installs, configures, troubleshoot & maintained the server environment.
- Analysed & resolved problems associated with server hardware & application software.
- Detected, diagnosed & reported server problems.
- Worked as a team member with other technical staff, such as networking to ensure connectivity and compatibility between systems.
- Write and maintain system documentation.
- Provide computing support for over 1500 (Baltic Exchange &Sgx) [ London and Singapore employee]
- Provided printer configuration, troubleshooting, repair support
   Troubleshooting, repair Windows 10 and 2003,2008 and 2012 Server
   connectivity issues as well as Microsoft Office XP/2003/2007/2016 and
   other software packages.
- Set up user accounts on company's servers & ran necessary system backups.
- Performed checks on database server and reported any errors (MySQL)
- Handled AdvantEdge calls and made sure they were solved in a timely efficient manner
- Reduced software license and maintenance costs.
- Maintain Active Directory services 2013 and Exchange O365
- Work on and maintained Hyper V and VMware servers.
- Support Single Sign-On using Active Directory Federation Services with Multifactor Authentication
- Manage Office 365 Unified messaging system.
- Manage Cisco and Netgear switches
- Assist in installation of security system and CCTV.
- Working knowledge of network switches, routers, firewalls, and network protocols (TCP/IP, DNS, WINS, DHCP).

- Strong knowledge of Symantec NetBackup and Backup Exec Solutions, and Antivirus applications.
- Good knowledge of Membership systems. BMS, CRM, SAGE.

## 13/12/2017- 24/01/2018

### IT Technician Hilton London bankside

(Splendid Hospitality Group)

- Assist Personnel with installation, configuring and ongoing usability of system hardware and software
- Offer Daily Operation and systems support to personnel
- Verify functionality of hardware and software components
- Troubleshoot hardware and software issues in person, remotely (Bomgar) and via phone
- Assist employees with computer problems and answer their questions
- Conduct daily network backup operations (Symantec backup) and changing tapes
- Strives to resolve malware and virus issues with personal workstations and a company's network. (Sophos)
- update and maintain servers 2008,2012 (Admin), create accounts for new users in active directory to be part of domain and create group policy for them.
- Maintain micros symphony server(oracle), Onq server and create accounts for new users.
- Create VPN connections on specific laptops and provide them permission through company firewall (watch guard) Admin, very good understanding of firewall
- Create accounts on Hotsos, novicom, guesttek and fiarmass for all users and update as well
- Good knowledge of office 365 adding users, delete and provide them license according job specification
- Communicates with individuals by phone and email to solve technical problems
- Raising po for all IT equipment's by using brichstreet
- Repair all offline access points and good knowledge of routing, switching, ports
- Maintain all printers, change toner, waste etc
- Maintain all DCET phone server and repair them well (Crowthorne)

### 01/11/2017-01/12/2017

# IT support Assistant East London school of science (Work placement)

- Installing and configuring computer hardware operating systems and applications.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks.
- Talking staff or clients through a series of actions, either face-to-face or over the telephone, to help set up systems or resolve issues.
- Troubleshooting system and network problems and diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults.
- Providing support, including procedural documentation and relevant reports.
- Following diagrams and written instructions to repair a fault or set up a system.
- Supporting the roll-out of new applications.
- Setting up new users' accounts and profiles and dealing with password issues.
- Prioritizing and managing many open cases at one time.
- Rapidly establishing a good working relationship with customers and other professionals, such as software developers.
- Testing and evaluating new technology.
- Good knowledge of Active directory, Windows server 2012, sccm 2012 and 365.

### **Interests and Achievements**

Computing: In my spare time, I enjoy installing and configuring operating systems such as Windows XP, Vista. I also do a lot of troubleshooting, repairing and changing parts of computers for my family and friends.

Hobbies: I love to travel to different countries, going to the gym, playing snooker, watching movies and going out with my friends.

Additional Info: I am willing to relocate for the right job opportunity.